<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">CountryPedia</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="pl_country_pl">Polska</string>
    <string name="en_country_pl">Poland</string>
    <string name="pl_country_ger">Niemcy</string>
    <string name="en_country_ger">German</string>
    <string name="pl_country_spa">Hiszpania</string>
    <string name="en_country_spa">Spain</string>
    <string name="pl_country_uk">Wielka Brytania</string>
    <string name="en_country_uk">United Kingdom</string>
    <string name="pl_country_usa">Stany Zjednoczone</string>
    <string name="en_country_usa">USA</string>
    <string name="pl_country_rus">Rosja</string>
    <string name="en_country_rus">Russian</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_pl">Polska, Rzeczpospolita Polska – państwo unitarne w Europie Środkowej, położone między Morzem Bałtyckim na północy a Sudetami i Karpatami na południu, w dorzeczu Wisły i Odry. Powierzchnia administracyjna Polski wynosi 312 679 km², co daje jej 70. miejsce na świecie i dziewiąte w Europie. Zamieszkana przez ponad 38,5 miliona ludzi, zajmuje pod względem liczby ludności 34. miejsce na świecie, a szóste w Unii Europejskiej.</string>
    <string name="en_descr_pl">Poland (Polish: Polska), officially the Republic of Poland (Polish: Rzeczpospolita Polska; Kashubian: Pòlskô Repùblika), is a country in Central Europe, bordered by Germany to the west; the Czech Republic and Slovakia to the south; Ukraine, Belarus to the east; and the Baltic Sea and Kaliningrad Oblast (a Russian exclave) and Lithuania to the north. The total area of Poland is 312,679 square kilometres (120,726 sq mi), making it the 69th largest country in the world and the 9th largest in Europe. With a population of over 38.5 million people, Poland is the 34th most populous country in the world, the sixth most populous member of the European Union</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_ger">Niemcy (Republika Federalna Niemiec, RFN; niem.: Deutschland lub Bundesrepublik Deutschland, BRD) – państwo federacyjne położone w zachodniej i środkowej Europie. Składa się z 16 krajów związkowych (landów), a jego stolicą i największym miastem jest Berlin. Państwo ma powierzchnię 357 021 km² i panuje w nim klimat umiarkowany. Z ponad 80 milionami mieszkańców jest najludniejszym krajem Unii Europejskiej</string>
    <string name="en_descr_ger">Germany (German: Deutschland), officially the Federal Republic of Germany (German: Bundesrepublik Deutschland), is a federal parliamentary republic in western-central Europe. The country consists of 16 states and its capital and largest city is Berlin. Germany covers an area of 357,021 square kilometres (137,847 sq mi) and has a largely temperate seasonal climate. With 80.3 million inhabitants, it is the most populous member state in the European Union</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_spa">Hiszpania, Królestwo Hiszpanii (hiszp. Reino de España, gal. Reino de España, kat. Regne dEspanya, arag. Reino dEspaña, bask. Espainiako Erresuma, okc. Regne dEspanha, ast. Reinu dEspaña) – największe z trzech państw położonych na Półwyspie Iberyjskim. Na zachodzie Hiszpania graniczy z Portugalią, na południu z należącym do Wielkiej Brytanii Gibraltarem, oraz przez Ceutę i Melillę z Marokiem. Na północy, przez Pireneje, kraj graniczy z Francją i Andorą. W skład Hiszpanii wchodzą także Baleary na Morzu Śródziemnym, Wyspy Kanaryjskie na Oceanie Atlantyckim oraz tzw. terytoria suwerenne</string>
    <string name="en_descr_spa">Spain (Spanish: España), officially the Kingdom of Spain (Spanish: Reino de España),is a sovereign state and a member state of the European Union. It is located on the Iberian Peninsula in southwestern Europe. Its mainland is bordered to the south and east by the Mediterranean Sea except for a small land boundary with Gibraltar; to the north and north east by France, Andorra, and the Bay of Biscay; and to the west and northwest by Portugal and the Atlantic Ocean. It is one of three countries (Morocco, France) to have both Atlantic and Mediterranean coastlines.</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_uk">Wielka Brytania, Zjednoczone Królestwo (ang. United Kingdom), Zjednoczone Królestwo Wielkiej Brytanii i Irlandii Północnej (ang. United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland) – unitarne państwo wyspiarskie położone w Europie Zachodniej. W skład Wielkiej Brytanii wchodzą: Anglia, Walia i Szkocja położone na wyspie Wielka Brytania oraz Irlandia Północna leżąca w północnej części wyspy Irlandia.</string>
    <string name="en_descr_uk">The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom (UK) or Britain, is a sovereign state located off the north-western coast of continental Europe. The country includes the island of Great Britain (a term sometimes loosely applied to the whole state), the north-eastern part of the island of Ireland, and many smaller islands.</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_usa">Stany Zjednoczone, Stany Zjednoczone Ameryki (ang. United States, US, United States of America, USA) – federacyjne państwo w Ameryce Północnej graniczące z Kanadą od północy, Meksykiem od południa, Oceanem Spokojnym od zachodu, Oceanem Arktycznym od północnego zachodu i Oceanem Atlantyckim od wschodu.</string>
    <string name="en_descr_usa">The United States of America (USA), commonly referred to as the United States (US), America, or simply the States, is a federal republic consisting of 50 states, 16 territories, and a federal district. The 48 contiguous states and the federal district of Washington, D.C., are in central North America between Canada and Mexico. The state of Alaska is the northwestern part of North America and the state of Hawaii is an archipelago in the mid-Pacific.</string>
    <string name="pl_descr_rus">Rosja (ros. Росси́я, Rossija; Federacja Rosyjska, ros. Российская Федерация, Rossijskaja Fiedieracyja, posłuchaj po rosyjsku i) – państwo rozciągające się od wschodniej Europy poprzez północną część Azji po Ocean Spokojny. Federacja Rosyjska jest największym państwem na świecie pod względem powierzchni oraz szóstym największym w historii świata. Pod względem liczby ludności zajmuje 9. miejsce. Rosja należy do największych gospodarek świata, pod względem PKB zajmuje 5. miejsce na świecie. Państwo rosyjskie dysponuje największymi na świecie zasobami naturalnymi i źródłami energii.</string>
    <string name="en_descr_rus">Russia (Russian: Россия, tr. Rossiya), also officially known as the Russian Federation(Russian: Российская Федерация, tr. Rossiyskaya Federatsiya), is a country in northern Eurasia. It is a federal semi-presidential republic, comprising 83 federal subjects. From northwest to southeast, Russia shares land borders with Norway, Finland, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania and Poland (both with Kaliningrad Oblast), Belarus, Ukraine, Georgia, Azerbaijan, Kazakhstan, China, Mongolia, and North Korea. It shares maritime borders with Japan by the Sea of Okhotsk and the U.S. state of Alaska across the Bering Strait. At 17,075,400 square kilometres (6,592,800 sq mi), Russia is the largest country in the world, covering more than one-eighth of the Earths inhabited land area.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_country_description_vertical">CountryDescriptionVertical</string>

</resources>
